508 Silver Spring Ave. ❖ Silver Spring, MD. 20910 ❖ (202) 262-2639 ❖ kimler@gmail.com

Objective

To implement powerful cutting-edge solutions and focus on innovation in an organization that empowers its customers, enriches its employees, and would benefit from a creative, strategic interdisciplinary team player.

Profile

Committed, responsive and responsible team member who takes ownership of goals as demonstrated by 10+ years as a consultant. Strong interpersonal and communication skills. Interactive, present and personable approach to communication.

Engages in continual self improvement, enjoys learning and takes on new skills easily. Uses the highest standards and best practices as a rule, but not afraid to think or go outside of the box if it leads to the best solution. Excellent systems evaluation and process development skills. Works well both independently with little to no supervision or on a team.

Develops vision, implements plans, and manages processes that ensure added efficiencies and productivity; demonstrated by successful service as technical director and as CSM (Certified ScrumMaster)

Skills Summary

- Web Development
- Web Programming
- Graphic Design
- ◆ E-Marketing
- Personable
- ◆ Search Engine Optimization (SEO-SEM)
- Hardware & Software
- Web Hosting
- Learn new skills quickly
 Interactive & Present
- Technology Integration
- Strategy & Visioning
- Process Development
- Technology Training

Professional Skills Experience

TECHNOLOGY: WEB DEVELOPMENT/DESIGN/HOSTING/DATABASES/OS

- Advanced experience with LAMP development platform and front-end integration.
- Adept programming skills PHP, JS, (X)HTML, HTML5, CSS, XML, 508 compliance certified, cross platform testing & development, javascript, Procedural Programming, basic OOP, Basic Design Patterns.
- Adept with Adobe Dreamweaver, Photoshop and Illustrator, Textmate.
- Skilled MySQL, SSH, GIT, MS-Office(Word, Excel, Power Point), and more.
- ◆ Mastery of OS-X 10.5-10.7, from good old MS DOS 6.1-Windows 7, Linux skills
- ◆ Basic Asp and MS-SQL, Access Skills.
- Basic web video production skills.
- Experienced with Content Management Systems (Custom, Wordpress, Drupal, Joomla, OSCommerce, Open realty), JQuery, SMARTY, PHPMailer, 508 Compliance Certified, FlashEff, Unity 3d iPhone Programming.

508 Silver Spring Ave. ❖ Silver Spring, MD. 20910 ❖ (202) 262-2639 ❖ kimler@gmail.com

Professional Skills Experience, continued

PROJECT MANAGEMENT:

Experience business owner:

- Experienced in customer acquisition concepts.
- Experienced with phone etiquette, customer support, consulting.
- Experienced in collections and automated process development.
- Experienced in all facets of conceiving, managing and implementing a business.

Planning:

- Experienced in developing and implementing a work plan and supporting documentation.
- Certified ScrumMaster (CSM)
- Experienced in developing and supporting a team.

Process and Contingency Planning:

- Experienced in developing strategies for measuring and accessing processes.
- Experienced in proactive development for future possibilities
- Experienced in identification of efficiency breakdowns.

OTHER SKILLS

- Computer hardware troubleshooting, maintenance and installation
- Software configuration, installation.
- Network troubleshooting and installation, maintenance
- Electronics and computer engineering skills and experience
- ◆ Novice Spanish skills, lived in Mexico City for 1+ year, Costa Rica for 1+ years
- ◆ International Business experience
- Enjoy interfacing with others to explore solutions and possibilities
- SEO/SEM, E-Marketing, and E-Commerce experience
- Developed, published iPhone apps, screen savers and excel macros

Employment History

Senior Software Engineer - Mgr. Product Dev, 2009 - present Chronicle.com - Wash. D.C..

- Website design, development, PHP programming (LAMP)
- Both Front-end and backend development,
- Developed and launched data api server for The Chronicles interactive projects
- Lead Developer for The Chronicle iPad app
- Lead Developer for The Chronicle's CollegeCompletion.chronicle.com
- Developer for account history on Chronicle payment system
- Systems Developer for The digital studio workflow

Owner/Developer/Consultant, 2001 - 2009

EMURJUN - Silver Spring, MD.

- Website design, e-commerce, develop processes for automated product
- Fulfillment, online catalogs, and product brochures
- Systems level analysis and problem resolution
- Marketing research, development, and sales

Founder/Developer, 2006 - 2007

CostaRicaWeb - San Jose, Costa Rica.

- Development of business guide, systems and processes
- Managed sales force, technical development
- ◆ PHP, XML, HTML, MySQL developer

508 Silver Spring Ave. ❖ Silver Spring, MD. 20910 ❖ (202) 262-2639 ❖ kimler@gmail.com

Developer/Consultant, 2004 - 2006

Marketing G2 (MG2) (remote contract Emuriun)

Philadelphia, PA.

- Database information scrubbing for New York Times and SF Chronicle
- Developed Canadian Online Campaign Manager
- ASP, HTML, JAVA, DHTML, MS-SQL programming

Systems Developer / Consultant, 2001 - 2003

Kellogg's (remote contract Emuriun)

- Battle Creek, MI.
- MS-SQL, HTML Interface Developer for Carton Information Systems
- Developed internal Carton Information System

Network Engineer, Computer Technician, 2000 - 2001 (also 1995 - 1997) Hi-Tech Computers -Tucson, AZ.

- Network Specialist for corporate clients, maintained systems
- Websites and internet design, data recovery, systems technician
- Designed in-house trouble ticket and system tracking software

Technology Director, 1999 - 2000

Additions Solutions - Los Angeles, CA.

- Developed, implemented, and maintained corporate network
- Developed website and national search database

Technology Director, 1997 - 1999

Espiritu - Phoenix, AZ.

- Developed solar/satellite systems and installed in developing countries
- Developed and maintained educational systems website, network and computers

Education

ITT TECH - TUCSON, AZ

Associates of Electronics and Computer Engineering, 91-93

GPA: 3.9/4.0

Certified Electronics Technician (IEEE) 1993.

UNIVERSITY OF MARYLAND UNIVERSITY COLLEGE - ADELPHI, MD

Bachelors of Computer Science, est. 2013

GPA: 3.8/4.0

Employment Narrative

SOFTWARE ENGINEER 10-11,

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER 11-12,

PRODUCT ENGINEERING MANAGER - STUDIO LEAD 12 - CURRENT WASHINGTON DC

THE CHRONICLE OF HIGHER EDUCATION / CHRONICLE.COM

Design and implementation of all aspects of the web in a LAMP environment. Worked with NSTEIN CMS, and multiple server environment. Designed the next generation API which ties together the newspapers editorial staff to develop interactive page elements quickly. Developed a number of automated systems to transform raw XML feeds into In-Design templates. Created systems and lead the team to success in iPad publishing. Lead Developer for collegeCompletion.chronicle.com and developed / launched on AWS. Deigned and developed a design thinking group to work on editorial focused projects.

508 Silver Spring Ave. ❖ Silver Spring, MD. 20910 ❖ (202) 262-2639 ❖ kimler@gmail.com

TECHNOLOGY LEAD / WEB AND E-COMMERCE DEVELOPER (EMURJUN PROJECT) 08-09 (AS CONSULTANT) GAITHERSBURG MD

TIDAL WAVE SOLUTIONS / PEANUTBUTTERSTICKS.COM

Design and implementation of all aspects of the web, software distribution system, and e-commerce system. Developed order fulfillment processes and system. Managed team of designers in ongoing website and marketing campaign. After successful launch, serve as technology specialist in the development of cross platform software now available to the public.

Served as Programming Lead to design and develop user-interface system for e-commerce subscription-based products. Member of team to develop and implement product development strategies.

SYSTEMS DEVELOPER / CONSULTANT 01-09 TUCSON, AZ

EMURJUN / LYCOSWEB (VISIT WWW.EMURJUN.COM FOR MORE INFORMATION)

Website Design, Web Programming, Customer Consulting. Develop interactive websites for clients from concept to final implementations. Map out business needs of customers, generate website and user interface components using Photoshop, Illustrator and other Adobe products. Developed sites ranging from simple "brochure" style to more complex solutions including customer contact systems, multi-user upload with tracking systems, search engine optimization, forms with protection from spam, PDF Generators which create documents from input information, employee test management systems, content management systems, maps showing geographic availability of seminars, calendars, e-commerce systems in the form of carts and also single items purchases/donations.

Worked as individual consultant and on teams. Team projects involved working with other designers—served as systems' architect and programming/implementation expert on these projects. Wide range of experience and able to communicate well in both technical and non-technical terms.

Projects / Clients

<u>Viscendo:</u> Arizona Wellness Council, SWS Energy Solutions (Tucson Electric Company), Zona78(rev2), Intec Services, Inc.

<u>Creative Slice:</u> Gresham & Beach, ShesaSheila.com, Wildcat Storage, Tucson Green Homes, Tuesday Business Leads Group, Johnston Consulting Group, Misco

<u>Emurjun:</u> SeedCookie.com, Epic Cafe, Foothills Mall Az, Mass Transcription, Sunglow Ranch, Zona78, West End Studio, Metro Auto Car Sales, Digital Mail Service, Master Consultants, Tachiz Travel, PeanutButterSticks.com, Madcad.com.

Lycosweb: Personal and business class web hosting on dedicated linux box.

FOUNDER AND WEB PROGRAMMER 06-07 COSTA RICA

COSTARICAWEB WEBSITE & PRINTED GUIDE

Founder of business directory which listed English-speaking businesses both electronically and in print. Guides distributed through the consulates in the US as well as abroad. Allied with Casa Canada and the Associated Residents of Costa Rica to disseminate guide, served as Casa Canada technology lecturer during monthly orientation for new Costa Rican residents. Served on Casa Canada Board of Directors.

508 Silver Spring Ave. ❖ Silver Spring, MD. 20910 ❖ (202) 262-2639 ❖ kimler@gmail.com

Customized open source solutions to list directory businesses and modified its processes to allow for automated payments. Supervised two sales employees. Later developed CostaRicanGPS alongside the guide, a GPS system which allowed businesses to be listed geographically through an electronic portion of the guide.

SYSTEMS DEVELOPER / CONSULTANT 04-06 PHILADELPHIA, PA

MARKETING G2 (MG2)

Assisted senior team in the set-up of new accounts, problem solving, and developing new components for use on corporate website, newspaper subscription websites, and MG2 signature project "e-Concierge." Additionally, led project to add new Canadian branch to newspaper customer management signup system. Created e-newspaper ads for San Francisco Chronicle which served as promotions for signing up with newspapers online. Developed components in the MG2 E-Concierge campaign product line.

SYSTEMS DEVELOPER / CONSULTANT 01-03 BATTLE CREEK, MI

KELLOGG'S

Worked on 8-person team to develop and implement a new information tracking system related to Kellogg's carton creation process. Prototyped the system using RPC. The system gathered information from a number of different legacy systems and created a single gateway for internal decision makers, third party vendors, and information managers.

NETWORK ENGINEER / HARDWARE TECHNICIAN 00-01/95-97 TUCSON, AZ

HI-TECH COMPUTERS

Developed websites for customers. Programmed access-based ticketing system to track incoming computers for repair. Handed troubleshooting and repaired computers at board level. Consulted onsite with customers and diagnosed, repaired / resolved problems related to equipment, networks etc. Trained customers on office processes, use of technology, web page design and using Photoshop for the web.

CHIEF TECHNOLOGY OFFICER 99-00 LOS ANGELES, CA

ADDICTIONS SOLUTIONS

Designed and developed website/service which allowed addiction recovery facilities and related businesses to list their services for market visibility. Managed data entry staff and provided support and setup of anything which had a plug for an office of up to 20 at one point.

DIRECTOR OF TECHNOLOGY 97-99 PHOENIX, AZ

ESPIRITU

Developed company's 3 websites and provided IT technical support to staff of 50+ onsite employees. Provided seminar audio/video setup and technical support for community development courses throughout the US, Mexico, and Central America.